Germer, Adolph Papers on Microfilm 5809 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Adolph Germer Papers on Microfilm
1898-1966
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Germer, Adolph
5809 mf
3.33 cubic feet
30 microfilm reels
Papers (documents), microfilm.
Correspondence, speeches, subject files, and personal materials of Adolph Germer.
5710643
Biographical / Historical
Mr. Germer was born in Welan, Germany In 1881 and came to the United States in 1888. His father was a miner, and Adolph went to work in the coal mines of Staunton, Illinois, when he was eleven years old. He joined the United Mine Workers of America in 1894 and held various offices; among them the United Mine Workers representative to the World Miners Congress in Amsterdam in 1912. He participated in the Colorado strike in 1913.
He joined the Socialist Party in 1900, and was its national secretary from 1916 to 1919. He was arrested, tried and convicted of subversion in the famous trial of 1918. With Eugene V. Debs and Victor L. Berger he wrote the Socialist Party report on the West Virginia Coal Strike in 1913.
In 1933 he joined the Oil Field, Gas Well and Refinery Workers and became an international organizer He participated in the formation of the Congress of Industrial Organizations and was on its staff as an organizer. He was its delegate to the World Federation of Trade Unions meeting in Prague in 1947.
Scope and Contents
The Germer collection is divided into six overlapping series of manuscripts:
Series 1: Correspondence, 1901-1966.
Series 2: Speeches, 1914[?]-1961.
Series 3: Personal material regarding Adolph Germer, 1900-1960.
Series 4: Subject files on the labor movement, 1898-1961.
Series 5: Diaries, 1930-1958.
Series 6: Scrapbook, 1930-1964.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5256: Adolph Germer Papers
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives 227 Ives Hall Tower Road Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheelref@cornell.edu https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, February 25, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 17, 2019
Labor unions -- Organizing -- United States; Strikes and lockouts -- Coal mining -- United States; Coal miners -- Labor unions -- United States; Collective bargaining -- Coal mining industry -- United States; Germer, Adolf; Congress of Industrial Organizations (U.S.)
5710643
- Correspondence, 1901-1931 (Reel 1)
  - 0001. Correspondence. 147 frames., 1901-1910; 1 (Reel 1)
  - 0148. Correspondence. 191 frames., 1911-1913; 2 (Reel 1)
  - 0339. Correspondence. 180 frames., 1914-1918; 3 (Reel 1)
  - 0519. Correspondence. 116 frames., 1919-1929; 4 (Reel 1)
  - 0635. Correspondence. 207 frames., 1930; 5 (Reel 1)
  - 0842. Correspondence. 238 frames., 1931; 6 (Reel 1)
- Correspondence, 1932-August 1935 (Reel 2)
  - 0001. Correspondence. 164 frames., 1932; 1 (Reel 2)
  - 0165. Correspondence. 260 frames., 1933; 2 (Reel 2)
  - 0425. Correspondence. 39 frames., 1934; 3 (Reel 2)
    Scope and Contents
    January-February 1934.
  - 0464. Correspondence. 147 frames., 1934; 4 (Reel 2)
    March 2-16, 1934
  - 0611. Correspondence. 132 frames., 1934; 5 (Reel 2)
    March 17-31, 1934
  - 0743. Correspondence. 120 frames., 1934; 6 (Reel 2)
    April-December, 1934
  - 0863. Correspondence. 212 frames., 1935; 7 (Reel 2)
    January-August 1935
- Correspondence, September 1935-December 1936 (Reel 3)
  - 0001. Correspondence. 248 frames., 1935; 1 (Reel 3)
    September-December 1935
  - 0249. Correspondence. 240 frames., 1936; 2 (Reel 3)
    January-March 1936
  - 0489. Correspondence. 141 frames., 1936; 3 (Reel 3)
    April-June 1936
  - 0630. Correspondence. 278 frames., 1936; 4 (Reel 3)
    July-December 1936
- Correspondence, January 1937-August 1940 (Reel 4)
  - 0001. Correspondence. 293 frames., 1937; 1 (Reel 4)
  - 0294. Correspondence. 147 frames., 1938; 2 (Reel 4)
  - 0441. Correspondence. 167 frames., 1939; 3 (Reel 4)
  - 0608. Correspondence. 176 frames., 1940; 4 (Reel 4)
    January-June 1940
  - 0785. Correspondence. 152 frames., 1940; 5 (Reel 4)
    July 1940
  - 0937. Correspondence. 148 frames., 1940; 6 (Reel 4)
    August 1940
- Correspondence, September 1940-April 1941 (Reel 5)
  - 0001. Correspondence. 120 frames., 1940; 1 (Reel 5)
    September 1940
  - 0121. Correspondence. 188 frames., 1940; 2 (Reel 5)
    October 1940
  - 0309. Correspondence. 190 frames., 1940; 3 (Reel 5)
    November-December 1940
  - 0499. Correspondence. 183 frames., 1941; 4 (Reel 5)
    January-February 1941
  - 0682. Correspondence. 243 frames., 1941; 5 (Reel 5)
    March-April 1941
- Correspondence, May 1941-December 1942 (Reel 6)
  - 0001. Correspondence. 176 frames., 1941; 1 (Reel 6)
    May-December 1941
  - 0177. Correspondence. 210 frames., 1942; 2 (Reel 6)
    January-March 1942
  - 0387. Correspondence. 95 frames., 1942; 3 (Reel 6)
    April-May 1942
  - 0482. Correspondence. 165 frames., 1942; 4 (Reel 6)
    June-July 1942
  - 0647. Correspondence. 205 frames., 1942; 5 (Reel 6)
    August-September 1942
  - 0852. Correspondence. 175 frames., 1942; 6 (Reel 6)
    October-December 1942
- Correspondence, January 1943-April 1944 (Reel 7)
  - 0001. Correspondence. 204 frames., 1943; 1 (Reel 7)
    January-March 1943
  - 0205. Correspondence. 223 frames., 1943; 2 (Reel 7)
    April-June 1943
  - 0428. Correspondence. 231 frames., 1943; 3 (Reel 7)
    July-December 1943
  - 0659. Correspondence. 335 frames., 1944; 4 (Reel 7)
    January-April 1944
- Correspondence, May 1944-March 1945 (Reel 8)
  - 0001. Correspondence. 203 frames., 1944; 1 (Reel 8)
    May-June 1944
  - 0204. Correspondence. 217 frames., 1944; 2 (Reel 8)
    July-August 1944
  - 0421. Correspondence. 143 frames., 1944; 3 (Reel 8)
    September 1944
  - 0564. Correspondence. 214 frames., 1944; 4 (Reel 8)
    October-December 1944
  - 0778. Correspondence. 228 frames., 1945; 5 (Reel 8)
    January-March 1945
- Correspondence, April 1945-August 1945 (Reel 9)
  - 0001. Correspondence. 191 frames., 1945; 1 (Reel 9)
    April-May 1945
  - 0192. Correspondence. 305 frames., 1945; 2 (Reel 9)
    June 1945
  - 0497. Correspondence. 321 frames., 1945; 3 (Reel 9)
    July 1945
  - 0818. Correspondence. 259 frames., 1945; 4 (Reel 9)
    August 1945
- Correspondence, September 1945-December 1946 (Reel 10)
  - 0001. Correspondence. 196 frames., 1945; 1 (Reel 10)
    September 1945
  - 0197. Correspondence. 134 frames., 1945; 2 (Reel 10)
    October-December 1945
  - 0331. Correspondence. 338 frames., 1946; 3 (Reel 10)
    January-May 1946
  - 0669. Correspondence. 294 frames., 1946; 4 (Reel 10)
    June-December 1946
- Correspondence, January 1947-May 1948 (Reel 11)
  - 0001. Correspondence. 317 frames., 1947; 1 (Reel 11)
    January-July 1947
  - 0318. Correspondence. 221 frames., 1947; 2 (Reel 11)
    August-December 1947
  - 0539. Correspondence. 222 frames., 1948; 3 (Reel 11)
    January-March 1948
  - 0761. Correspondence. 274 frames., 1948; 4 (Reel 11)
    April-May 1948
- Correspondence, June 1948-December 1948 (Reel 12)
  - 0001. Correspondence. 167 frames., 1948; 1 (Reel 12)
    June 1948
  - 0168. Correspondence. 218 frames., 1948; 2 (Reel 12)
    July-August 1948
  - 0386. Correspondence. 231 frames., 1948; 3 (Reel 12)
    September-October 1948
  - 0617. Correspondence. 218 frames., 1948; 4 (Reel 12)
    November-December 1948
- Correspondence, January 1949-June 1950 (Reel 13)
  - 0001. Correspondence. 306 frames., 1949; 1 (Reel 13)
    January-May 1949
  - 0307. Correspondence. 252 frames., 1949; 2 (Reel 13)
    June-December 1949
  - 0559. Correspondence. 262 frames., 1950; 3 (Reel 13)
    January-March 1950
  - 0821. Correspondence. 180 frames., 1950; 4 (Reel 13)
    April-June 1950
- Correspondence, July 1950-June 1953 (Reel 14)
  - 0001. Correspondence. 257 frames., 1950; 1 (Reel 14)
    July-December 1950
  - 0258. Correspondence. 219 frames., 1951; 2 (Reel 14)
    January-April 1951.
  - 0477. Correspondence. 218 frames., 1951; 3 (Reel 14)
    May-December 1951
  - 0695. Correspondence. 81 frames., 1952; 4 (Reel 14)
  - 0776. Correspondence. 145 frames., 1953; 5 (Reel 14)
    January-June 1953
- Correspondence, July 1953-[December] 1957 (Reel 15)
  - 0001. Correspondence. 81 frames., 1953; 1 (Reel 15)
    July-December 1953
  - 0082. Correspondence. 193 frames., 1954; 2 (Reel 15)
  - 0275. Correspondence. 248 frames., 1955; 3 (Reel 15)
  - 0523. Correspondence. 195 frames., 1956; 4 (Reel 15)
  - 0718. Correspondence. 210 frames., 1957; 5 (Reel 15)
- Correspondence, 1958-1966 and Undated (Reel 16)
  - 0001. Correspondence. 174 frames., 1958; 1 (Reel 16)
  - 0175. Correspondence. 180 frames., 1959; 2 (Reel 16)
  - 0355. Correspondence. 148 frames., 1960; 3 (Reel 16)
  - 0503. Correspondence. 138 frames., 1961; 4 (Reel 16)
  - 0641. Correspondence. 136 frames., 1962; 5 (Reel 16)
  - 0777. Correspondence. 93 frames., 1963; 6 (Reel 16)
  - 0870. Correspondence. 99 frames., 1964-1966; 7 (Reel 16)
    1964-1966 and Undated.
- Speeches, 1914-1961 and Personal Material regarding Germer, 1918-1956 (Reel 17)
  - 0001. Speeches., 1933-1942; 1 (Reel 17)
    [1914], 1933-1942
  - 0002. Refusal by the American Federation of Labor convention of 1914 to support eight-hour day legislation. 7 frames., 2 (Reel 17)
  - 0009. National Lock Company strike in Rockford, Illinois. 4 frames., 1933; 3 (Reel 17)
  - 0013. Class conflict and United States labor history. 14 frames., 1934; 4 (Reel 17)
  - 0027. Goodyear Tire and Rubber Company anti-union practices in Akron, Ohio. 7 frames., 1936; 5 (Reel 17)
  - 0034. Fisher Auto Body strike and violence in Flint, Michigan. 2 frames., 1937; 6 (Reel 17)
  - 0036. United States Supreme Court decision overturning a New York minimum wage provision. 5 frames., 1936; 7 (Reel 17)
    [1936?]
  - 0041. Federal Screw Products strike and police brutality in Detroit, Michigan. 3 frames., 1937; 8 (Reel 17)
    [1937?]
  - 0044. Fisher Auto Body strike and violence in Flint, Michigan. 2 frames., 1937; 9 (Reel 17)
  - 0046. Greetings to the International Fur Workers Union Convention. 2 frames., 1938; 10 (Reel 17)
  - 0048. Labor and the Ford Motor Company. 6 frames., 1937; 11 (Reel 17)
  - 0054. Oil Workers' Union, Harvey C. Framing, American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations. 7 frames., 1937; 12 (Reel 17)
  - 0061. The Congress of Industrial Organizations issue and United Auto Workers. 10 frames., 1939; 13 (Reel 17)
  - 0071. Congress of Industrial Organizations and Labor's Non-Partisan League in Ironwood, Michigan. 8 frames., 1939; 14 (Reel 17)
  - 0079. Union support for the Greater New York Fund. 11 frames., 1940; 15 (Reel 17)
  - 0090. More funds for hospitals in New York, New York. 8 frames., 1940; 16 (Reel 17)
  - 0098. "Town Meeting" radio program: United States farm policy. 15 frames., 1942; 17 (Reel 17)
  - 0113. To the Michigan State Industrial Union Conference. 17 frames., 1939; 18 (Reel 17)
  - 0130. Why the Wagner Act should not be amended. 7 frames., 1939; 19 (Reel 17)
  - 0137. To the Washington State Industrial Union Conference. 5 frames., 1940; 20 (Reel 17)
  - 0142. To the War Board Conference in Berkeley, California. 16 frames., 1942; 21 (Reel 17)
  - 0158. The Shevlin-Hixon election between the International Woodworkers of America-Congress of Industrial Organizations and the American Federation of Labor in Bend, Oregon. 6 frames., 1941; 22 (Reel 17)
  - 0164. Labor Day remarks and minutes of meetings of the International Labor Day celebration in El Paso, Texas. 8 frames., 1942; 23 (Reel 17)
  - 0172. California Conference on Labor in the War. 2 frames., 1942; 24 (Reel 17)
  - 0174. Drafts of "Town Meeting" radio program: United States farm policy. 11 frames., 1942; 25 (Reel 17)
  - 0185. Speeches., 1943-1961; 26 (Reel 17)
    1943-[1961?]
  - 0186. To the Brewery Workers Convention, Galveston, Texas. 8 frames., 1942; 27 (Reel 17)
    [1942?]
  - 0194. To the Montana State Industrial Union Conference. 9 frames., 1943; 28 (Reel 17)
    [1943?]
  - 0203. To the Michigan State Industrial Union Conference. 13 frames., 1944; 29 (Reel 17)
    [1944?]
  - 0216. To the International Woodworkers of America Convention in Eugene, Oregon. 19 frames., 1945; 30 (Reel 17)
  - 0235. To the Utah State Industrial Union Conference. 10 frames., 1945; 31 (Reel 17)
  - 0245. Regarding the Communist party and American Federation of Labor competition with Congress of Industrial Organizations unions. 3 frames., 1948; 32 (Reel 17)
    [1948]
  - 0248. To the International Woodworkers of America Convention in Saint Louis, Missouri. 4 frames., 1947; 33 (Reel 17)
  - 0254. Reports of the Massachusetts House Legislative Committee on Labor Industries regarding the petition of Ellsworth P. Curtis and others for the regulation of strikes and labor organizations. 10 frames., 1948; 34 (Reel 17)
  - 0264. Labor Day remarks [not delivered] in Boston, Massachusetts. 8 frames., 1948; 35 (Reel 17)
  - 0282. To the Michigan State Industrial Union Conference. 17 frames., 1948; 36 (Reel 17)
    [1948?]
  - 0299. To the Minnesota State Industrial Union Conference. 14 frames., 1949; 37 (Reel 17)
  - 0313. To the Utah State Industrial Union Conference. 17 frames., 1949; 38 (Reel 17)
  - 0330. Radio address sponsored by the British Columbia District Council of the International Woodworkers of America. 8 frames., 1950; 39 (Reel 17)
  - 0338. To the British Columbia District Council of the International Woodworkers of America. 10 frames., 1951; 40 (Reel 17)
    [1951?]
  - 0348. Regarding Colorado labor history and the Communist party. 6 frames., 1951; 41 (Reel 17)
  - 0354. Radio address regarding the International Woodworkers of America in Flagstaff, Arizona. 12 frames., 1951; 42 (Reel 17)
  - 0366. To the Utah State Industrial Union Conference. 11 frames., 1950; 43 (Reel 17)
  - 0377. To an unidentified state industrial union conference. 9 frames., 1954; 44 (Reel 17)
    [1954?]
  - 0386. To the International Woodworkers of America Convention. 30 frames., 1950-1959; 45 (Reel 17)
    [1950s?]
  - 0416. To the British Columbia District Council of the International Woodworkers of America. 15 frames., 1954; 46 (Reel 17)
  - 0431. Regarding Phillip Murray and Allan S. Haywood. 10 frames., 1954; 47 (Reel 17)
  - 0441. To the International Woodworkers of America Convention in Palm Beach, Florida. 14 pages., 1961; 48 (Reel 17)
    [1961?]
  - 0455. Oral History interview of Adolph Germer and cover letter by Jack W. Skeels for the University of Michigan - Wayne State University Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations. 31 frames., 1960-1962; 49 (Reel 17)
  - 0486. Personal Material regarding Germer - Biographical (News clippings, etcetera) [Unsorted]. 115 frames., 1931-1966; 50 (Reel 17)
  - 0578. Personal Material regarding Gerber. The "Chicago Socialists" Trial [United States versus Victor L. Berger, Adolph Germer, Irwin St. John tucker, J. Louis Engdahl, and William F. Kruse]. 115 frames., 1917-1919; 51 (Reel 17)
  - 0693. Personal Material regarding Gerber. Financial [Unsorted]. 164 frames., 1931-1958; 52 (Reel 17)
    1931-1958 and Undated.
  - 0857. Personal Material regarding Germer. Memorabilia from European Trip [Unsorted]. 100 frames., 1946-1947; 53 (Reel 17)
- Personal Material regarding Germer, 1900-1960 and Labor (General), 1916-1958 (Reel 18)
  - 0001. Personal Material regarding Germer. Miscellaneous [Unsorted]. 160 frames., 1900-1960; 1 (Reel 18)
    1900-1960 and Undated
  - 0161. Labor - General. Rockford, Illinois (Miscellaneous).107 frames., 1931-1936; 2 (Reel 18)
    1931-1936 [1930-1936]
  - 0268. Labor - General. Rockford, Illinois (Rockford Labor News). 34 frames., 1916-1934; 3 (Reel 18)
    1916, 1932-1934
  - 0302. Labor - General. Rockford, Illinois (National Lock Company). 68 frames., 1933-1935; 4 (Reel 18)
  - 0370. Labor - General. National Recovery Administration (Miscellaneous). 165 frames., 1933-1935; 5 (Reel 18)
  - 0535. Labor - General. National Recovery Administration (Notes on Cases). 221 frames., 1935; 6 (Reel 18)
    February-May 1935.
  - 0766. Labor - General. Miscellaneous Union and Labor Material, etcetera. 305 frames., 1930-1958; 7 (Reel 18)
    1930-1958 and Undated.
- Labor (Political), 1936-1956 and Labor (Congress of Industrial Organizations, General and Regional), 1936-1946 (Reel 19)
  - 0001. Labor - Political. Political Action Committee and Miscellaneous [Unsorted]. 161 frames., 1936-1956; 1 (Reel 19)
  - 0162. Labor - Political. Proposed State Legislation. 96 frames., 1930-1939; 2 (Reel 19)
    [1930s?]
  - 0258. Labor - Political. Public Power: Missouri Valley Authority (MVA), Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA), etcetera. 270 frames., 1943-1954; 3 (Reel 19)
  - 0528. Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations. General. 363 frames., 1936-1946; 4 (Reel 19)
- Labor (Political), 1948 and Labor (Congress of Industrial Organizations, General and Regional), 1938-1961 (Reel 20)
  - 0001. Labor - Political. Wallace Propaganda. 53 frames., 1948; 1 (Reel 20)
  - 0054. Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations. General. 158 frames., 1949; 2 (Reel 20)
  - 0212. Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations. General. 120 frames., 1950; 3 (Reel 20)
  - 0332. Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations. General. 90 frames., 1950; 4 (Reel 20)
  - 0422. Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations. General. 8 frames., 1951-1952; 5 (Reel 20)
  - 0430. Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations. General. 97 frames., 1953; 6 (Reel 20)
  - 0527. Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations. General. 97 frames., 1954; 7 (Reel 20)
  - 0624. Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations. General. 176 frames., 1955-1961; 8 (Reel 20)
    1955, 1959-1961
  - 0800. Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations. Michigan. 38 frames., 1938-1939; 9 (Reel 20)
  - 0838. Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations. New York. 63 frames., 1940; 10 (Reel 20)
- Labor (Congress of Industrial Organizations, General and Regional), 1940-1953 and Labor (Individual Unions) (Reel 21)
  - 0001. Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations. Western Region - California. 264 frames., 1948-1950; 1 (Reel 21)
  - 0265. Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations. Western Region - Detroit, Michigan. 31 frames., 1947-1948; 2 (Reel 21)
  - 0296. Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations. Western Region - Miscellaneous. 226 frames., 1940-1953; 3 (Reel 21)
  - 0522. Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations. Western Region - Colorado. 224 frames., 1951; 4 (Reel 21)
  - 0746. Labor. International Union of Mine, Mill, and Smelter Workers. 48 frames., 1945-1949; 5 (Reel 21)
  - 0794. Labor. Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America. 10 frames., 1939; 6 (Reel 21)
    [1939?]
- Labor (Individual Unions) (Reel 22)
  - 0001. Labor. Federation of Flat Glass Workers. 41 frames., 1936-1937; 1 (Reel 22)
  - 0042. Labor. International Union of United Brewery, Flour, Cereal, and Soft Drink Workers of America. 98 frames., 1930-1953; 2 (Reel 22)
    1930s, 1946, 1952-1953
  - 0140. Labor. International Union of United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers. 233 frames., 1934-1955; 3 (Reel 22)
  - 0373. Labor. International Woodworkers of America - General. 448 frames., 1937-1963; 4 (Reel 22)
    1937-1963 and Undated.
- Labor (Individual Unions) (Reel 23)
  - 0001. Labor. International Woodworkers of America - Southern Area. 163 frames., 1949-1959; 1 (Reel 23)
    1949, 1954-1959.
  - 0164. Labor. International Woodworkers of America - Financial. 284 frames., 1943-1951; 2 (Reel 23)
    1943, 1948-1951
  - 0428. Labor. International Woodworkers of America - Financial. 253 frames., 1943-1957; 3 (Reel 23)
    1943, 1948-1957
  - 0681. Labor. International Woodworkers of America - Bargaining Agreements, etcetera. 196 frames., 1951-1956; 4 (Reel 23)
  - 0877. Labor. International Woodworkers of America - Hearing [controversy between International Woodworkers of America international officers and Germer]. 307 frames., 1941; 5 (Reel 23)
- Labor (Individual Unions) (Reel 24)
  - 0001. Labor. International Woodworkers of America - Hearing [controversy between International Woodworkers of America international officers and Germer] (continued). 41 frames., 1941; 1 (Reel 24)
  - 0042. Labor. International Woodworkers of America - Convention reports. 15 frames., 1940; 2 (Reel 24)
  - 0057. Labor. International Woodworkers of America - Convention Reports. 234 frames., 1941; 3 (Reel 24)
  - 0291. Labor. International Woodworkers of America - Convention reports. 16 frames., 1943; 4 (Reel 24)
  - 0307. Labor. International Woodworkers of America - Convention Reports. 240 frames., 1945; 5 (Reel 24)
  - 0546. Labor. International Woodworkers of America - Convention Reports. 53 frames., 1947; 6 (Reel 24)
  - 0599. Labor. International Woodworkers of America - Convention reports. 180 frames., 1949; 7 (Reel 24)
  - 0779. Labor. International Woodworkers of America - Executive Board Minutes. 79 frames., 1945; 8 (Reel 24)
- Labor (Individual Unions) (Reel 25)
  - 0001. Labor. International Woodworkers of America - Executive Board Minutes. 231 frames., 1945; 1 (Reel 25)
  - 0232. Labor. International Woodworkers of America - Executive Board Minutes. 73 frames., 1949; 2 (Reel 25)
  - 0305. Labor. Mechanics Educational Society of America. 104 frames., 1935-1936; 3 (Reel 25)
  - 0409. Labor. Oil Workers International Union. 66 frames., 1938-1945; 4 (Reel 25)
    1938, 1945 [, and 1950s]
  - 0475. Labor. Telephone Workers Organizing Committee. 248 frames., 1946-1950; 5 (Reel 25)
  - 0723. Labor. United Mine Workers of America. 190 frames., 1898-1929; 6 (Reel 25)
    1898-1929 [1942]
- Labor (Individual Unions) and Diaries, 1930-1935 (Reel 26)
  - 0001. Labor. United Mine Workers of America. 312 frames., 1930-1944; 1 (Reel 26)
  - 0313. Labor. United Rubber Workers of America. 170 frames., 1933-1937; 2 (Reel 26)
  - 0483. Diary. Volume 1. 145 Frames., 1930; 3 (Reel 26)
    Locations: Illinois, Missouri, Ohio, Iowa, Kansas, Indiana, West Virginia, New York, Kentucky.
  - 0628. Diary. Volume 2. 77 frames., 1931; 4 (Reel 26)
    Locations: Illinois, Iowa, Indiana, Ohio, West Virginia.
  - 0705. Diary. Volume 3. 36 frames., 1932; 5 (Reel 26)
    Locations: Illinois, Michigan. [Diaries dating 1933-1934 missing in original]
  - 0741. Diary. Volume 4. 185 frames., 1935; 6 (Reel 26)
    Locations: Illinois, Iowa, Wisconsin, District of Columbia, Ohio, Michigan, Indiana.
- Diaries, 1936-1940 (Reel 27)
  - 0001. Diary. Volume 5. 197 frames., 1936; 1 (Reel 27)
    Locations: Michigan, Ohio, Pennsylvania, Illinois, Missouri, Indiana, Ontario, Kentucky, West Virginia, Wisconsin, Georgia, Alabama.
  - 0198. Diary. Volume 6. 197 frames., 1937; 2 (Reel 27)
    Locations: Michigan, Ohio, Illinois, Texas, Missouri, Mexico, Indiana, Kansas, West Virginia, District of Columbia, Wisconsin, New York, New Jersey.
  - 0395. Diary. Volume 7. 196 frames., 1938; 3 (Reel 27)
    Locations: Michigan, Ohio, District of Columbia, Illinois, Texas, California, Wyoming, Colorado, Indiana, Wisconsin, Pennsylvania.
  - 0591. Diary. Volume 8. 199 frames., 1939; 4 (Reel 27)
    Locations: Michigan, Pennsylvania, District of Columbia, Illinois, Missouri, Ohio, California, New York, New Jersey, Connecticut.
  - 0790. Diary. Volume 9. 196 frames., 1940; 5 (Reel 27)
    Locations: New York, Pennsylvania, Ohio, Connecticut, New Jersey, District of Columbia, Illinois, Michigan, Oregon, Washington, British Columbia, Idaho, California.
- Diaries, 1941-1945 (Reel 28)
  - 0001. Diary. Volume 10. 197 frames., 1942; 1 (Reel 28)
    Locations: Washington, Illinois, District of Columbia, Minnesota, Montana, Oregon, New York, California, Missouri, Colorado.